<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on TimDbg</title><link>/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on TimDbg</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 11:15:04 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My new blog</title><link>/posts/first-post/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2022 11:15:04 -0700</pubDate><guid>/posts/first-post/</guid><description>Hi everyone! Ever since I started tweeting about WinDbg and debugging, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking that I have some longer things I want to write about that don&amp;rsquo;t really fit on twitter. I&amp;rsquo;ve done a few of these as videos on my YouTube channel, but those are very time consuming to make and most people don&amp;rsquo;t seem to watch the whole video. So I think a lot of what I want to talk about is probably best suited for a blog format.</description><content>&lt;p>Hi everyone! Ever since I started tweeting about WinDbg and debugging, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking that I have some longer things I want to write about that don&amp;rsquo;t really fit on twitter. I&amp;rsquo;ve done a few of these as videos on my &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCyQ7p63-9V9PZJvgHLKgsaw">YouTube channel&lt;/a>, but those are very time consuming to make and most people don&amp;rsquo;t seem to watch the whole video. So I think a lot of what I want to talk about is probably best suited for a blog format.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In any case, I plan to talk about a few different things. For one, I&amp;rsquo;ll write about WinDbg and other Windows debugging tools. It&amp;rsquo;s an area I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on for more than a decade, and there are lots of things I&amp;rsquo;ve learned that I think you might find helpful for low level debugging, reverse engineering, and other development work on Windows. The second area that I plan to write about is the art and science of debugging itself. While building debugging tools, I&amp;rsquo;ve had the chance to spend a lot of time thinking about what it means to be effective at debugging problems. Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s about knowing the right tool to use, but oftentimes it&amp;rsquo;s just as important to understand the process of debugging.&lt;/p></content></item></channel></rss>